<bill session="113" type="h" number="1120" updated="2014-08-17T23:20:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-04-12T12:10:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-04-12T12:10:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Greater Uncertainty in Labor-Management Relations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Preventing Greater Uncertainty in Labor-Management Relations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Preventing Greater Uncertainty in Labor-Management Relations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the National Labor Relations Board from taking any action that requires a quorum of the members of the Board until such time as Board constituting a quorum shall have been confirmed by the Senate, the Supreme Court issues a decision on the constitutionality of the appointments to the Board made in January 2012, or the adjournment sine die of the first session of the 113th Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="01954"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02018" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01925" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02062" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01791" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01720" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02058" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01990" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01922" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02140" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02051" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00636" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01733" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01806" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02142" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02130" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00912" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01778" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01986" joined="2013-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02017" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01009" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01892" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01952" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01855" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01779" joined="2013-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01688" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 16.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09T15:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 113-30.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-09T15:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="18">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 18.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 146 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1120 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-11T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 146 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T10:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 146.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1963-1975" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T10:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1120 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The resolution provides that an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of the Rules Committee Print 113-6 shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T10:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1120.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T11:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1973" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T11:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Bustos moved to recommit with instructions to Education and the Workforce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1973" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1973" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T11:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bustos motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to protect the employment and election rights of veterans and the American workforce against outsourcing, abuse by foreign firms, unsafe working conditions and discrimination.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T11:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1974" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 229 (Roll no. 100).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="101" datetime="2013-04-12T12:10:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 219 - 209 (Roll no. 101).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1963" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-04-12T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="113" relation="rule" number="146"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="557"/>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="976"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="180"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="188"/>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="unknown" number="850"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h40"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/12/2013--Passed House amended.
Preventing Greater Uncertainty in Labor-Management Relations Act - Requires the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) to cease all activity that requires a quorum of Board members. Prohibits the Board from appointing any personnel nor implementing, administering, or enforcing any decision, rule, vote, or other action decided, undertaken, adopted, issued, or finalized on or after January 4, 2012, that requires a quorum of the Board members.

Terminates the requirements of this Act upon: (1) confirmation of all Board members constituting a quorum with the advice and consent of the Senate, (2) a decision by the Supreme Court on the constitutionality of Board appointments made in January 2012, or (3) the adjournment sine die of the first session of the 113th Congress.

Prohibits, in the event of this Act's termination, the appointment, or implementation, administration, or enforcement of any Board action occurring on or after January 4, 2012, that requires authorization by not less than a quorum of the Board members, unless and until the action is considered and acted upon by a Board constituting a quorum, or the Supreme Court issues a decision on the constitutionality of the Board appointments made in January 2012.</summary>
</bill>
