<bill session="113" type="h" number="1974" updated="2014-08-14T13:08:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Disaster Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the collateral requirement for certain loans under section 7(d) of the Small Business Act, to address assistance to out-of-State small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="02117"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01970" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01912" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01742" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01976" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00635" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01730" joined="2013-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02059" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02034" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02097" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02118" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02023" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02004" joined="2013-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="113" relation="identical" number="415"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2013--Introduced.
Small Business Disaster Reform Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act with respect to obtaining the best available collateral for a disaster loan of not more than $200,000 relating to damage to or destruction of the property of, or economic injury to, a small business concern. Prohibits the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), in obtaining such collateral, from requiring the small business owner to use the owner's primary residence as collateral if the owner has other assets with a value equal to or greater than the loan amount that could be used as collateral for the loan.

Allows the Administrator to authorize a Small Business Development Center (SBDC) to provide assistance to small businesses outside the state of that SBDC, without regard to geographical proximity, if the small business is in an area for which the President has declared a major disaster.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the Administrator shall ensure that a SBDC is appropriately reimbursed for any legitimate expenses in carrying out such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
