<bill session="113" type="h" number="1395" updated="2014-08-14T13:02:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Weekends Without Hunger Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a weekend and holiday feeding program to provide nutritious food to at-risk school children on weekends and during extended school holidays during the school year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="01940"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01471" joined="2013-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02159" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01878" joined="2013-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00229" joined="2013-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01976" joined="2013-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01857" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01895" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01708" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02147" joined="2013-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02101" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00701" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01653" joined="2013-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01504" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00944" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00997" joined="2013-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01042" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01988" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02112" joined="2013-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="4765"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/2013--Introduced.
Weekends Without Hunger Act - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture, subject to the availability of appropriations, to implement a pilot program providing commodities, on a competitive basis, to nonprofits for the provision of nutritious food to at-risk school children on weekends and during extended school holidays during the school year. (At-risk school children are those who participate in the school lunch program and reside in an area served by a school in which at least 50% of the students receive free or reduced price meals under the school lunch or breakfast programs.)

Includes elementary and secondary schools, school food authorities, food banks or pantries, homeless shelters, and other Secretary-approved emergency feeding agencies as eligible nonprofit recipients of such commodities.

Requires commodity recipients to satisfy safe food storage, handling, and delivery standards established by the Secretary.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) complete an interim evaluation of the pilot program by November 30, 2016, and (2) submit a final report to Congress by December 31, 2018, that contains an evaluation of such program and any recommendations the Secretary may have for legislative action.

Authorizes appropriations for the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
