<bill session="113" type="s" number="1641" updated="2014-08-14T13:58:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">West Virginia National Heritage Area Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Appalachian Forest National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="01424"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00174" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01983" joined="2013-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00802" joined="2013-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/2013--Introduced.
West Virginia National Heritage Area Act of 2013 - Establishes the Appalachian Forest National Heritage Area in the states of Maryland and West Virginia.

Designates the Appalachian Forest Heritage Area, Inc., as the local coordinating entity for the Area.

Requires the Appalachian Forest Heritage Area, Inc., to submit a management plan that provides for the protection, enhancement, and interpretation of cultural, natural, historical, educational, scenic, and recreational resources of the Area.

Amends the National Coal Heritage Area Act of 1996 and the Wheeling National Heritage Area Act of 2000 to extend through FY2017 the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to make grants or provide assistance with respect to the National Coal Heritage Area and the Wheeling National Heritage Area.</summary>
</bill>
