<bill session="113" type="h" number="3601" updated="2014-08-18T00:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parental Notification and Intervention Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for parental notification and intervention in the case of an unemancipated minor seeking an abortion.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="01801"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01858" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02135" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01753" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01882" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01742" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01670" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02057" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01924" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01707" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01656" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00484" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02032" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02020" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02028" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02046" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00612" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01868" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02100" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02050" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01885" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01931" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02195" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01685" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01758" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02001" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02035" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01954" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02017" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02161" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01688" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02115" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Parental Notification and Intervention Act of 2013 - Prohibits any person or organization in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, or who solicits or accepts federal funds, from performing, permitting facilities to be used to perform, or assisting in the performance of an abortion on an unemancipated minor unless: (1) written notification is provided to the parents of the minor informing them that an abortion has been requested, unless there is clear and convincing evidence of physical abuse of the minor by such parent; (2) there is compliance with a 96-hour waiting period after any required notice has been received by the parents; and (3) there is compliance with any injunction granted by a federal district court if a notified parent initiates a judicial intervention process to enjoin the abortion. Prescribes penalties of not more than a $100,000 fine and/or imprisonment for not more than one year for each willful violation.

Provides for an exception from such parental notification requirements if a physician (other than the physician with principal responsibility for making the decision to perform the abortion) determines that: (1) a medical emergency exists that would result in the minor's death if her condition were not immediately treated, even though the treatment may result in the death of her unborn child; (2) parental notification is not possible as a result of the emergency; and (3) certifications regarding compliance with such rules and the reasons upon which such determinations are based have been entered in the minor's medical records. Requires parental notification through certified mail or personal delivery. Defines "parent" to include any legal guardian of an unemancipated minor. Authorizes a notified parent to bring an action in federal court which shall enjoin the abortion: (1) until the court's judgment is final, or (2) permanently unless the court determines that granting such relief would be unlawful. Prohibits this Act from being construed to preempt any state law that establishes, implements, or continues in effect greater parental notification requirements or intervention rights regarding abortion.</summary>
</bill>
