<bill session="113" type="hr" number="682" updated="2014-08-17T22:39:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding worker protections in Qatar and the 2022 Federation Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) World Cup.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="00808"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01469" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02196" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00229" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00281" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01708" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02172" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00688" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01653" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00766" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01504" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00868" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01510" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02171" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00944" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01588" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02104" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01729" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Calls on: (1) the United States to prioritize the rights of migrant workers in their relations with Qatar by offering technical assistance and expertise in combating human trafficking and the provision of victim-centered services, and (2) U.S. corporations involved in constructing World Cup related infrastructure in Qatar to ensure that working conditions are in compliance with international human rights standards by holding subcontractors accountable for labor violations and incorporating mechanisms for enforcement of such contractual obligations.

Calls on the Qatari authorities to implement existing legislation and enact new legislation to prevent human rights violations.

Calls on the migrant laborers' countries of origin, notably Bangladesh, India, Nepal, the Philippines, and Sri Lanka, to protect their nationals from deceptive recruitment agencies in their countries and intervene on behalf of their nationals whose rights are abused when working in Qatar and other Persian Gulf states.

Urges the Federation Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) to: (1) ensure that the World Cup is a symbol of global cooperation, (2) deliver a strong message to Qatar to make sure that the 2022 World Cup is not staged with the assistance of modern slavery by continuing the organization's involvement in Qatar, and (3) advocate for fair labor practices on all World Cup related projects.</summary>
</bill>
