<bill session="113" type="hr" number="707" updated="2014-08-17T22:40:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning all forms of anti-Semitism and rejecting attempts to justify anti-Jewish hatred or violent attacks as an acceptable expression of disapproval or frustration over political events in the Middle East or elsewhere.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="00850"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01838" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01487" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00709" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01848" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Condemns: (1) all forms of anti-Semitism and rejects attempts to justify anti-Jewish hatred or violent attacks as an acceptable expression of disapproval over political events, and (2) the comparison of Israel to Nazis perpetrating a Holocaust or genocide.

 Applauds those foreign leaders, especially in France, Italy, and Germany, who have condemned anti-Semitic acts, and calls on those who have yet to take firm action against anti-Semitism in their countries to do so.

 Reaffirms support for the mandate of the United States Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism.

Supports Holocaust educational programs at home and abroad.

Urges the Secretary of State to:

 maintain the fight against anti-Semitism as a U.S. foreign policy priority, urge governments to ensure that adequate laws are in place to punish anti-Semitic violence and hate crimes as well as establish mechanisms to investigate and punish perpetrators, continue U.S. reporting on anti-Semitism as a human rights and religious freedom issue, provide training for diplomatic and law enforcement personnel posted abroad to report on anti-Semitic incidents, deepen engagement with the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe and support its specialized efforts to monitor and address anti-Semitism, and oppose efforts to prevent any individual from exercising his or her religion without fear of prosecution or violence.</summary>
</bill>
