<bill session="113" type="s" number="1691" updated="2014-08-18T03:18:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Patrol Agent Pay Reform Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to improve the security of the United States border and to provide for reforms and rates of pay for border patrol agents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor thomas_id="01829"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02075" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="01633" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="02174" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor thomas_id="00754" joined="2013-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="113" relation="unknown" number="3463"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2013--Introduced.
Border Patrol Agent Pay Reform Act of 2013 - Sets forth additional&#160;requirements relating to the rates of pay and terms of employment&#160;for U.S. Border Patrol agents (i.e., federal employees who detect and prevent illegal entry and smuggling of aliens, commercial goods, narcotics, weapons, or contraband into the United States).

Requires Border Patrol agents to elect each year to: (1) be assigned to either a specified&#160;level one or level two border patrol rate of pay governing regular rates of pay&#160;and overtime work requirements,&#160;or (2) decline to be assigned to either level.&#160;Expresses the sense of Congress that U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) should ensure that not more than 10% of agents stationed at a location decline to be assigned to either the level 1 or level 2 border patrol rate of pay. Empowers CBP, without limitation, to require agents to perform overtime work in accordance with agency needs, including if needed in the event of a local or national emergency.</summary>
</bill>
